Margaret Henderson Floyd Records UA047
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Margaret Henderson Floyd Records
1983 -- 1989
1982 -- 1998
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Floyd, Margaret H.
Buildings and Ground Committee
Department of Grounds and Buildings
University Facilities
Campus Planning and Development Committee (AS&E Faculty)
UA047
1.83 Linear Feet 3 boxes, 5 oversized folders
Arrangement
This collection is organized in four series: Architectural Inventory Research Files; Architectural Inventory of Tufts Buildings; Subject Files; and Plans and Drawings.
Custodial History
DCA received 1 box of architectural drawings, correspondence, and committee records on 2002-09-20.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains records created and used by Professor Margaret Henderson Floyd during her years at Tufts University. Records include architectural blue prints and drawings, photographs and negatives (with contact sheets) of campus buildings, committee minutes and reports, correspondence, memos and notes relating to her position at Tufts University.
Biographical / Historical
Margaret Henderson Floyd (1932-1997) was a professor in the Department of Art and Art History at Tufts University from 1977 until 1997.
Born in New York City, Floyd graduated from Wellesley College with a BA in Art History in 1953. She went on to receive a master's degree in Art History from the University of New Mexico in 1957, and earned her Ph.D. in American Studies from Boston University in 1974.
At Tufts, Floyd taught courses on architectural history and American art. One of her most popular courses focused on Boston and Cambridge architecture. In 1981, Floyd was appointed to the Campus Planning and Development Committee by Dean Frank Colcord. In 1983, she began work on an architectural inventory of university buildings for the committee. She also served as chair of the Fine Arts Department from 1983 to 1987, when she was involved in establishing Tufts University Art Gallery.
Floyd gave frequent walking tours of Boston, and an annual architectural tour of Newport, R.I. mansions. She was active in local historic preservation projects and involved with the Boston Architectural Center. Her published works include Harvard: An Architectural History (co-authored with Bainbridge Bunting, 1985); Architectural Education and Boston (1989); Architecture after Richardson: Regionalism before Modernism--Longfellow, Alden, and Harlow in Boston and Pittsburgh (1994); and Henry Hobson Richardson: A Genius for Architecture (1997).
Margaret Henderson Floyd died of cancer on October 18, 1997. The Department of Art and Art History established the Margaret Henderson Floyd Memorial Lecture (1999) and the Architectural Studies Prize (2006) in her honor.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list.
Curriculum and Instruction -- Faculty; Facilities; Greater Boston arts
- Architectural Inventory Research Files, 1982 -- 1983; UA047.001; 1.2 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series research files for the Tufts architectural inventory conducted by MHF and a student assistant. Materials include negatives and contact sheets, news clippings, memos, research files, and reports produced between 1982 and 1983.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  75 years from the date of creation. Open for research.
  - Arcidi: Masterplan Financial, UA047.001.001.00165 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
    75 years from the date of creation.
  - Campus Development Report July 83, UA047.001.001.00166 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
    Open for research.
  - Campus Survey Forms Notes & Corr. Floyd/Arcidi, UA047.001.001.00167 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Tufts Architectural Inventory Contact Sheets, UA047.001.001.00168 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Tufts Architectural Inventory Negatives, UA047.001.001.00169 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Tufts Inventory Source Lists and Refs., UA047.001.001.00170 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
- Architectural Inventory of Tufts Buildings, 1983; UA047.002; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series subject files of university buildings. Building files contain architectural history records including photographs, location as well as index cards. Photographic negatives are located in series 1. The ID number on each building record is from Physical Plant's FIPS List, an index of plans and specs for University buildings. The PrO number is from the Property Office's list of campus buildings. The numbers above the building name are the location of corresponding negatives.
  - Alumnae Hall, UA047.002.001.00001 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Alumni House, UA047.002.001.00002 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Anderson Hall, UA047.002.001.00003 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Arena Theater, UA047.002.001.00004 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Arena Theater Costume Shop, UA047.002.001.00005 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Bacon Hall, UA047.002.001.00006 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Ballou Hall, UA047.002.001.00007 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Barnum Hall, UA047.002.001.00008 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Bolles House 226 College Ave, UA047.002.001.00009 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Bartol House 37 Sawyer Ave., UA047.002.001.00010 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 11 Bellevue St., UA047.002.001.00011 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 21 Bellevue St., UA047.002.001.00012 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Blakeslee House, UA047.002.001.00013 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Bush Hall, UA047.002.001.00014 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Braker Hall, UA047.002.001.00015 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Bray Mechanical Laboratory, UA047.002.001.00016 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Bromfield House 16 Dearborn Rd., UA047.002.001.00017 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 28 Bromfield Rd., UA047.002.001.00018 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 108 Bromfield, UA047.002.001.00019 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Bromfield-Pearson Building 503 Boston Avenue, UA047.002.001.00020 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Brown House 38 Professors Row, UA047.002.001.00021 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Cabot Intercultural Center, UA047.002.001.00022 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Capen House 8 Professors Row, UA047.002.001.00023 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 6-8 Capen St., UA047.002.001.00024 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Carmichael Hall, UA047.002.001.00025 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Carpenter House, UA047.002.001.00026 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Central Heating Plant, UA047.002.001.00027 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Central Services Building, UA047.002.001.00028 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Chandler House 125 Powder House Bvld., UA047.002.001.00029 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Cohen Arts Center, UA047.002.001.00030 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 159 College Ave., UA047.002.001.00031 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Computer User Center, UA047.002.001.00032 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 11 Conwell Ave., UA047.002.001.00033 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Cousens Gymnasium, UA047.002.001.00034 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Crane Chapel, UA047.002.001.00035 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Cirriculum Resource Center, UA047.002.001.00036 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Curtis Hall, UA047.002.001.00037 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 11 Curtis Ave., UA047.002.001.00038 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 89-91 Curtis St., UA047.002.001.00039 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 90-94 Curtis St., UA047.002.001.00040 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 97 Curtis St., UA047.002.001.00041 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 98 Curtis St., UA047.002.001.00042 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 102 Curtis St., UA047.002.001.00043 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 114 Curtis St., UA047.002.001.00044 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Counseling Center 120 Curtis St., UA047.002.001.00045 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 126-128 Curtis St., UA047.002.001.00046 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 146 Curtis St., UA047.002.001.00047 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 158 Curtis St., UA047.002.001.00048 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 162 Curtis St., UA047.002.001.00049 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 166 Curtis St., UA047.002.001.00050 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 176 Curtis St., UA047.002.001.00051 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Dana Laboratory, UA047.002.001.00052 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Davies House 13 Sawyer Ave., UA047.002.001.00053 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Daycare Center, UA047.002.001.00054 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 12 Dearborn Rd., UA047.002.001.00055 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Dewick Dining Hall, UA047.002.001.00056 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - East Hall, UA047.002.001.00057 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Eaton Hall, UA047.002.001.00058 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 7 Edison Ave., UA047.002.001.00059 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 11 Edison Ave., UA047.002.001.00060 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 15 Edison Ave., UA047.002.001.00061 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Eliot Pearson Child Study Ctr., UA047.002.001.00062 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Eliot Pearson School, UA047.002.001.00063 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Fairmount House 21-23 Fairmount St., UA047.002.001.00064 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Field House, UA047.002.001.00065 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Fletcher Hall, UA047.002.001.00066 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Garage (adj. to Office Svcs.), UA047.002.001.00067 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Goddard Chapel, UA047.002.001.00068 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Goddard Hall, UA047.002.001.00069 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Graves House 18 Latin Way, UA047.002.001.00070 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Hall House 98 Packard Ave., UA047.002.001.00071 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Hamilton Pool, UA047.002.001.00072 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Haskell Hall, UA047.002.001.00073 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Hayes House 17 Chetwynd Rd., UA047.002.001.00074 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Hill Hall, UA047.002.001.00075 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Hillside Dorm "A" Suites 10, 20, UA047.002.001.00076 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Hillside Dorm "B" Suites 30, 40, UA047.002.001.00077 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Hillside Dorm "C" Suites No. 50, 60, UA047.002.001.00078 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Hillside House 32 Dearborn Rd., UA047.002.001.00079 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Hodgdon Hall, UA047.002.001.00080 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Hooper Laboratory, UA047.002.001.00081 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Hooper House 128 Professors Row, UA047.002.001.00082 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Hooper Infirmary 124 Professors Row, UA047.002.001.00083 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Houston Hall, UA047.002.001.00084 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Jackson Gymnasium, UA047.002.001.00085 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Lane Hall, UA047.002.001.00086 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Latin Way Dormitory, UA047.002.001.00087 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Lewis Hall, UA047.002.001.00088 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Lincoln Filene Center, UA047.002.001.00089 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - MacPhie Dining Hall, UA047.002.001.00090 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - McCollester House 32 Capen St., UA047.002.001.00091 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Metcalf Hall, UA047.002.001.00092 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Milne House 10 Whitfield Rd., UA047.002.001.00093 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Michael Chemical Laboratory, UA047.002.001.00094 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Miller Hall, UA047.002.001.00095 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Miner Hall, UA047.002.001.00096 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Mugar Hall, UA047.002.001.00097 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Office Services, UA047.002.001.00098 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 80 Packard Ave., UA047.002.001.00099 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 84 Packard Ave., UA047.002.001.00100 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 96 Packard Ave., UA047.002.001.00101 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 100 Packard Ave., UA047.002.001.00102 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 108 Packard Avenue, UA047.002.001.00103 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 112 Packard Ave., UA047.002.001.00104 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 120 Packard Ave. Graduate School, UA047.002.001.00105 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 126 Packard Ave., UA047.002.001.00106 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 122 Powderhouse Bvld., UA047.002.001.00107 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Anthony House 14 Professors Row, UA047.002.001.00108 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 20 Professors Row, UA047.002.001.00109 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Richardson House 28 Professors Row, UA047.002.001.00110 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Packard Hall, UA047.002.001.00111 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Paige Hall, UA047.002.001.00112 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Pearson Chemical Laboratory, UA047.002.001.00113 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - President's House, UA047.002.001.00114 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 48 Professors Row, UA047.002.001.00115 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 72 Professors Row, UA047.002.001.00116 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 92 Professors Row, UA047.002.001.00117 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Research Building 490 Boston Ave., UA047.002.001.00118 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Robinson Hall, UA047.002.001.00119 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 14 Sawyer Ave., UA047.002.001.00120 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 20 Sawyer Avenue, UA047.002.001.00121 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 28 Sawyer Ave., UA047.002.001.00122 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 29 Sawyer Avenue, UA047.002.001.00123 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 36 Sawyer Avenue, UA047.002.001.00124 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 44 Sawyer Ave., UA047.002.001.00125 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 45 Sawyer Ave., UA047.002.001.00126 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 51 Sawyer Ave., UA047.002.001.00127 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Schmalz House 9-11 Whitfield Rd., UA047.002.001.00128 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 114 South St., UA047.002.001.00129 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Start House 15-17 Latin Way, UA047.002.001.00130 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Stratton Hall, UA047.002.001.00131 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 9-11 Sunset Rd., UA047.002.001.00132 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 16 Sunset Rd., UA047.002.001.00133 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Sweet Hall, UA047.002.001.00134 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 11 Talbot Ave. Fine Arts Dept., UA047.002.001.00135 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 13 Talbot Ave., UA047.002.001.00136 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 55 Talbot Ave., UA047.002.001.00137 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 61 Talbot Ave., UA047.002.001.00138 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 97 Talbot Ave., UA047.002.001.00139 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 101 Talbot Ave. Munro House, UA047.002.001.00140 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 44 Teele Ave., UA047.002.001.00141 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 13-15 Telsa Avenue, UA047.002.001.00142 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 16-18 Telsa Ave., UA047.002.001.00143 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Tilton Hall, UA047.002.001.00144 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 21 Touro Ave., UA047.002.001.00145 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Tousey House 14 Edison Ave., UA047.002.001.00146 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - University Store (Taberna), UA047.002.001.00147 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Wessell Library, UA047.002.001.00148 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - West Hall, UA047.002.001.00149 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 14 Whitfield Rd., UA047.002.001.00150 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 25 Whitfield Rd., UA047.002.001.00151 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 26 Whitfield Rd., UA047.002.001.00152 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 27-29 Whitfield Rd., UA047.002.001.00153 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 38 Whitfield Rd., UA047.002.001.00154 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 43-45 Whitfield Rd., UA047.002.001.00155 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Wilson House 136 Curtis Street, UA047.002.001.00156 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 10 Winthrop St., UA047.002.001.00157 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 43-45 Winthrop St., UA047.002.001.00158 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 44-46 Winthrop St., UA047.002.001.00159 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - 47 Winthrop St., UA047.002.001.00160 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Wren Hall, UA047.002.001.00161 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Wyeth House 21 Whitfield Rd., UA047.002.001.00162 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Yacht Club, UA047.002.001.00163 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Non-Tufts Buildings, UA047.002.001.00164 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
- Subject Files, 1985 -- 1998; UA047.003; 1.95 Linear Feet
  This series contains Margaret Henderson Floyd's subject files from the 1980s to the mid 1990s. Files include memos, news clippings, photographs, reports and committee minutes from the Campus Planning/Development Committee and the Buildings and Grounds Committee.
  - [11 Talbot Plans], UA047.003.001.00171 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
    Plans in this folder were rehoused in folder 00004 [11 Talbot Plans] oversize, series 4 'Plans and Drawings'.
  - AAUP, UA047.003.001.00172 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - [Bromfield-Pearson National Register of Historic Places report], UA047.003.001.00173 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Buildings and Ground- Arts Complex CBT Corr. & Photo, UA047.003.001.00174 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Buildings and Ground- Art Dept. Facilities 1993 Wechsler, UA047.003.001.00175 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Buildings and Ground- B&G Activities 1986/7, UA047.003.001.00176 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Buildings and Ground- B&G Activities 1993+, UA047.003.001.00177 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Buildings and Ground- Ballou Hall, UA047.003.001.00178 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Buildings and Ground- Bromfield Pearson: Moffatt Stc., UA047.003.001.00179 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Buildings and Ground- Tufts Historic District, UA047.003.001.00180 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - [Campus Buildings: Re-finishing plan, To M. Floyd from T. Blackett], UA047.003.001.00181 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Campus Development, 1985 -- 1988; UA047.003.001.00182 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Campus Development 1989/90, 1989 -- 1990; UA047.003.001.00183 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Campus Development Arts Complex Extra Copies, UA047.003.001.00184 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
  - Campus Planning Committee (1of 2), UA047.003.001.00185 (Box UA047 Shared 1)
    plans in this folder were rehoused in folder 00005 [Arena Theatre Plans] oversize series 4 "Plans and Drawings
  - Campus Planning Committee (2 of 2), UA047.003.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - Campus Planning Committee, 1988 -- 1989; UA047.003.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - Campus Planning & Development, UA047.003.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - Darkroom Siegfried Halus, UA047.003.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - [Daycare Building Exterior Color Board], UA047.003.002.00005 (Box 2)
    board moved to folder 00006 oversize series 4 "Plans and Drawings"
  - Gallery II, 1998; UA047.003.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - Knable, B: Student Honesty Minorities Etc., UA047.003.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - Mayer Campus Center Specifications Vol 1, UA047.003.002.00008 (Box 2)
  - Mayer Campus Center Specifications Vol. 2, UA047.003.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - Photo Lab, UA047.003.003.00002 (Box 3)
    plans moved to folder 00007 [Jackson Gym, Boiler Plant Plans] oversize series 4 "Plans and Drawings"
  - Rick Chrisman- Chaplain, UA047.003.003.00003 (Box 3)
    plans moved to folder 00008 [Proposed Renovations for Goddard Chapel] oversize series 4 "Plans and Drawings"
- Plans and Drawings, UA047.004; 1.2 Linear Feet
  This series contains architectural plans (blue prints) and drawings of selected university buildings. Most plans are oversize.
  - [11 Talbot Plans], UA047.004.003.00004 (Box Large Map Case 1 Drawer 8)
    exact photocopied prints can be found in folder 39090014011049; 11 prints
  - [Arena Theater Plans], UA047.004.003.00005 (Box Large Map Case 1 Drawer 6)
    3 items in folder
  - [Daycare Building Exterior Color Board], UA047.004.003.00006 (Box Large Map Case 1 Drawer 6)
    1 item in folder
  - [Jackson Gym, Boiler Plant Plans], UA047.004.003.00007 (Box Large Map Case 1 Drawer 6)
    1 item in the folder
  - [Proposed Renovations for Goddard Chapel], UA047.004.003.00008 (Box Large Map Case 1 Drawer 6)
    1 item